williams-sonoma.com.au 2014-03-28

# Privacy Policy | Williams-Sonoma

We are Williams-Sonoma Australia Pty Ltd, a subsidiary of Williams-Sonoma, Inc. Williams-Sonoma, Inc, and its subsidiaries own and operate under the brands Williams-Sonoma®, Pottery Barn®, pottery barn kids® and west elm® ("Williams-Sonoma, Inc. Brands"). 

We are committed to respecting your privacy and recognising your need for appropriate protection and management of contact information you share with us (the phrase "contact information" means any information by which you can be contacted or identified, such as your name, mailing address, email address, telephone number, etc.). The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform you what information we may collect from you, how we use such information, and the choices you have regarding our use of, and your ability to review, correct and opt out of our use of, the information. By using any of our web sites or sharing your contact information with us, you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this Privacy Policy. 

As a part of our commitment to your privacy, we support and adhere to this Privacy Policy as well as to the guidelines and practices adopted by the Direct Marketing Association’s "Privacy Promise to American Consumers." We have agreed to (1) provide customers with notice of their ability to opt out of information rental, sale, or exchange with other marketers; (2) honour customers' requests not to share their contact information with other marketers; and (3) honour customers' requests not to receive mail, telephone, or other solicitations from us. 

**Collecting Information About You**

There may be times (such as when you purchase or order a product, subscribe to a service, register to receive catalogues, or to participate in contests, sweepstakes or promotions, etc.) when we ask you to provide certain contact information about yourself, such as your name, shipping/billing address, telephone number, email address, credit card information, birth date, gender, occupation, personal interests, and other information. We may also maintain a record of your product purchases. 

Whether or not to provide such information is completely your own choice. But if you choose not to provide the information we request, you may be unable to purchase products, or access certain services, offers and content on our web sites. In addition, we may need to contact you via phone, email or mail to address questions or issues specific to your order, entry, etc., even if you have opted to not receive marketing communications from us. 

In general, you can visit many of our web pages without telling us who you are or revealing any contact information about yourself. You may also be able to deal with us in other ways without identifying yourself (ie anonymously or by using a pseudonym) if this is practicable. If you wish to do so, please contact us to find out if this is practicable in your circumstances. We may track the Internet domain address from which people visit us and analyse this data for preferences, trends, and site usage statistics, but individual users will remain anonymous, unless you voluntarily tell us who you are. 

**Using Information About You**

We use your contact information for internal purposes only, such as: 

  * confirming and tracking your order, subscription, or registration; 
  * analysing preferences, trends, and statistics; 
  * informing you of our new products, services, and offers if you have consented to receiving such; and 
  * providing you with other information from and about us, Williams- Sonoma, Inc. and Williams-Sonoma, Inc. Brands if you have consented to receiving such. 

We process your contact information only in ways compatible with the purposes for which it was collected or authorised by you. To the extent necessary for such purposes, we take reasonable steps to make sure that your contact information is accurate, complete, current, and otherwise reliable with regard to its intended use. 

From time to time we might establish a business relationship with other persons or entities whom we believe trustworthy and whom we have asked to confirm that their privacy policies are consistent with ours. These are known as our Select Partners. In such cases we might rent, exchange, share and/or cross-reference information, including contact information about you that will enable such persons or entities to contact you regarding products and services that may be of interest to you. If you choose to provide us with your information, you consent to the transfer and storage of that information by our Select Partners located in the United States. You acknowledge that by consenting to the disclosure of information about you (including contact information) to our Select Partners located outside of Australia we will no longer be under an obligation to take steps ensure that our Select Partners comply with the privacy principles set out in the _Privacy Act 1988_ (Cth) and, on this basis, you expressly agree to such disclosure. 

To serve you better, we may combine information you give us online, in our stores or through our catalogues. We may also combine that information with publicly available information and information we receive from or cross-reference with our Select Partners and others. We use that combined information to enhance and personalise the shopping experience of you and others with us, to communicate with you about our products and events that may be of interest to you, and for other promotional purposes. 

We may contract with companies or persons to provide certain services including credit card processing, shipping, data management, promotional services, etc. We call them our Service Providers. We provide our Service Providers with the information needed for them to perform these services. We also ask our Service Providers to confirm that their privacy practices are consistent with ours. If you choose to provide us with your information, you consent to the transfer and storage of that information by our Service Providers located in the United States. You acknowledge that by consenting to the disclosure of information about you (including contact information) to our Service Providers located outside of Australia we will no longer be under an obligations to take steps ensure that our Service Providers comply with the privacy principles set out in the _Privacy Act 1988_ (Cth) and, on this basis, you expressly agree to such disclosure. 

We allow third-party companies to serve ads and/or collect certain anonymous information when you visit our web sites. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to this and other web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or third party web beacon to collect this information. To learn more about this behavioural advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit [http://www.networkadvertising.org.](http://www.networkadvertising.org/)

We may share (and you consent to our sharing) contact information and other data with businesses controlling, controlled by, or under common control with Williams-Sonoma, Inc., which businesses may be located in the United States and/or in other countries. 

In certain instances we may disclose your contact information when we have reason to believe that it is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against persons or entities who may be causing injury to you, to us, to Williams-Sonoma, Inc, to any of the Williams-Sonoma, Inc. Brands or to others. We may also disclose your contact information when we believe the law or legal process requires it. 

**Opting Out Of Marketing And Transfers; Updating, Deleting and Accessing Information About You**

We want to communicate with you only if you want to hear from us and will only send marketing communications to you if you have first consented to receiving such. If you prefer not to receive direct marketing from us or from our Select Partners, or if you would like to opt out of our rental or exchange of your information with other marketers, please let us know. You can call us Toll Free at 1800 231 380, send us an email at [customerservice@williams-sonoma.com.au](mailto:customerservice@williams-sonoma.com.au) or follow the unsubscribe function in our marketing communications. Please be sure to include your full name, email address, mailing address, and specifically what information you do not want to receive. If you would like to update or correct your email address, mailing address or other information (including other contact information) with us please contact us the same way. You may also request us to provide access to the information, including contact information, that we hold about you in which case we may require you to pay the reasonable cost of providing access to any such information (but we will not charge you for lodging a request for access). If you like, you may use either of the following statements in your message to us: 

  * "I prefer not to receive email advertisements, such as updates regarding products and services, special promotions or upcoming events." 
  * "I prefer not to receive direct mail advertisements, such as periodic catalogues and mailings regarding products and services, special promotions or upcoming events." 

You may also click the designated link at the bottom of all email advertisements to be removed from future email updates. 

Please note that any requests to remove or update your contact information may take up to five business days from receipt of your email or postal request for electronic marketing (for example, emails and SMS) and up to 6-8 weeks from receipt of your email or postal request for non-electronic marketing (for example, brochures posted to you) to process. 

**Cookies**

When you visit our web sites, we send one or more "cookies" to your computer or other device. We may also use cookies in emails that you receive from us. A "cookie" is a small data file that is placed on the hard drive of your computer when you visit a web site. A "session cookie" expires immediately when you end your session (i.e., close your browser). A "persistent cookie" stores information on the hard drive so when you end your session and return to the same web site at a later date the cookie information is still available. Generally, we use cookies to improve the quality of our service when you visit our web site and other web sites of interest to you. We also use cookies to remind us of who you are, tailor our products, services and advertising to suit the personal interests of you and others, estimate our audience size, assist our online merchants to track visits to and sales at our web sites and to process your order, track your status in our promotions, contests and sweepstakes, and/or analyse your visiting patterns. 

Certain of our Service Providers may use cookies and collect information on our behalf. They are prohibited by our contract with them from sharing that information with anyone other than us or our other Service Providers. In addition, in connection with the services that they provide to us, certain of our Service Providers may work with third parties who may use cookies to collect anonymous information to tailor advertising for you and others elsewhere on the Internet. These third parties do not have access to any contact information about you. If you would like to opt out of accepting cookies altogether, you can generally set your browser to not accept cookies or to notify you when you are sent a cookie, giving you the chance to decide whether or not to accept it. However, certain features of our web sites or other services may not work if you delete or disable cookies. 

**Security**

We maintain reasonable physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect the confidentiality and security of information transmitted to us. To guard your information delivered to us electronically, our web sites use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL). SSL encrypts your credit card number, name and address so only we are able to decode your information. Unfortunately, however, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your contact information, to the extent permitted by law: 

  * we do not guarantee or warrant the security of any information you transmit to or from our web sites; and
  * you do so at your own risk. 

We urge you to keep any password that you establish with us in a safe place and not to divulge it to anyone. Also remember to log off your account and close your browser window when you have finished your visit. This is to ensure that others cannot access your account, especially if you are sharing a computer with someone else or are using a computer in a public place. 

**Protecting Children**

We take special care to protect the safety and privacy of children. Our web sites are general audience sites. We do not permit anyone under the age of 13 to register with us. We also do not send email correspondence to anyone who tells us that they are under the age of 13. 

Children under the age of 13 should always ask their parents or guardians for permission before providing any contact information to anyone online. We urge parents and guardians to participate in their children's online activities and use parental control or other web filtering technology to supervise children's access to the Internet. 

**Links to Third Party Web Sites**

Our web sites may contain links to web sites operated and maintained by third parties, over which we have no control. Privacy policies on such linked web sites may be different from our privacy policy. You access such linked web sites at your own risk. You should always read the privacy policy of a linked web site before disclosing any of your information on such web site. 

**Policy Changes**

If we decide to change our privacy policy in whole or in part, we will inform you by posting a notice on our web sites, as applicable. Those changes will go into effect on the effective date posted in the notice and at the end of the revised Privacy Policy. The new policy will apply to all current and past users of our web sites and will replace any prior policies that are inconsistent. Your continued use of our web sites or other services constitutes your acceptance of the practices described in the revised Privacy Policy. 

**Your Feedback**

To help us improve our privacy policy and practice, please give us your feedback. You can call us **Toll Free at 1800 231 380** or send us an email at [customerservice@williams-sonoma.com.au.](mailto:customerservice@williams-sonoma.com.au)

**Complaints**

If you wish to make a complaint about a breach of the privacy principles set out in the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth), you can call us **Toll Free at 1800 231 380** or send us an email at [customerservice@williams-sonoma.com.au](mailto:customerservice@williams-sonoma.com.au). You will need to provide us with sufficient details regarding your complaint together with any supporting evidence. 

We will refer your complaint to our legal department who will investigate the issue and determine the steps (if any) that we will undertake to resolve your complaint. We will contact you if we require any additional information from you and will notify you in writing of the outcome of the investigation. 

If you are not satisfied with our determination, you can contact us to discuss your concerns or complain to the Australian Privacy Commissioner via www.oaic.gov.au. 

Effective Date: 3 March 2014 (updated)
